SHIBA DEB

{ Portfolio: website, Github: shiba517, LinkedIn: shiba-deb-2099b6105/, Email: shiba.cdeb@gmail.com, Phone: 07960545799, Location: London, UK }

Full Stack Developer

I am a Fullstack Developer with proficiency in HTML, CSS, SQL, JavaScript, Python, Django, MongoDB, PHP, React, Vue and Laravel. I also bring experience in communications with the public which came in use whilst working in the hospitality industry, and have been exposed to the world of creativity with my time in hair and beauty. Creative, collaborative, and certainly open to challenges.

Technical Skills

Languages

- JavaScript
- Python
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SQL
- PHP

Databases

- MongoDB
- AWS
- MySQL

Frameworks/Libraries Version control

Github

- JQuery
- Django
- React
- Vue
- Node
- Bootstrap
- Materialize
- Streamlit
- Pandas
- Laravel
- Laravel Nova
- Tailwind

Education and Training

Sparta Global (April 2000 – June 2022) – Data Engineering
Code Institute (2021 - 2022) - Full Stack Developer - Merit
Westminster University (2016 - 2018) - Nutrition
London Metropolitan University (2009 - 2012) - Business and Marketing (2:1)

Projects

Personal Portfolio (<u>link</u>) - This is my personal portfolio. I created this using React and deployed it on netlify.com

Gallery Five (link) - This is the fourth project I had submitted for my Code Institute - Full Stack Software Developer course. This is a website selling pieces of art. It is a full stack website produced with the use of HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, JQuery, Node, Django, Heroku and AWS.

The Memory Game (<u>link</u>) - This is the project I submitted for my second assignment. Match the cards on top with the overturned cards. It was made with HTML5, CSS, JS and JQuery

Find Me Talent (<u>link</u>) - This is a project that lets you find football talents via filtering and viewing player data in a graphical format. Demonstrates skills in SQL, NoSQL, Python, Pandas, Streamlit, and ELT/ETL.

Spotify Mood Bot (<u>link</u>) - A voice recognition project where the bot will give you a playlist from Spotify depending on what you tell him. I created this using JavaScript and React.

Bubble Game (<u>link</u>) - This is a project that I have made because I wanted a taste of what it's like to create a game. I used HTML <canvas> element and mainly coded in JavaScript. The game is not complete and further info regarding the state of the game can be found in the README. I hope you will enjoy playing the game!

Professional Experience

Brackets Digital (2022 Oct - present)

Junior web developer

Developed, maintained and debugged websites using PHP, Laravel and our legacy CMS. My day-to-day tasks included

- Fixing bugs found on our websites backend and frontend
- Developing the backend for our newer websites which have been made using Laravel Nova
- Creating backend features requested by clients
- Migrating current legacy websites to Laravel
- Creating frontend features with the use of Vue.js

PGL Adventure Centre (2021 - 2022)

Catering assistant

Being part of a team to prepare a canteen and then serve to feed hundred+ children three times a day. High volume and tight timings were the main challenges which pushed me to

- Prioritise and be efficient with tasks
- Approach situations in a calmly manner

The May Fair Hotel (2016 - 2020)

Events team-leader

It was my responsibility to help the events manager to set up and run the event smoothly. Due to the hotel being the company's (Radisson Blu) flagship hotel, we had to be on top of our game on how we deliver the service and experience the company demands. A big part of that happening was following guidelines, personal intuition/initiative and organisation. I learnt a lot on how to

- Communicate effectively with different departments
- Encourage groups of people to work together
- Deal with demanding difficult guests without negatively affecting their experience

Windle and Moodie Hairdressers (2015 - 2016)

Trainee hairdresser (apprenticeship)

Assist high demanding senior hairdressers with their work on their clients whilst also learning from them all in a fast-paced environment. Achieved an NVQ in hairdressing with SAKS academy. Whilst working here, I was exposed to

- Constant new techniques and ideas
- Create a custom experience with clients
- Implement my learnings into practise

Interests and Hobbies

- Tech meetups Regular attendee to London Tech Network Wednesday meetups
- Hiking Not a stranger to various hiking groups
- Cycling Saved many train fares by cycling to other towns/cities
- Travelling Visited many small towns and cities around Europe

Transferable Skills

- Time management and Organisation
- Leadership and Empathy
- Collaborative and Problem-solving